ALDREN T. BAGUAL

+63 955 960 0756

drengual.github.io





As a Junior Full Stack Developer, I create responsive web applications using React.js and Node.js, focusing on both frontend design and backend functionality. Previously, I worked as a freelance frontend developer and provided IT support, honing my skills in web technologies and user experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Full Stack Developer

Creaxon, Inc | May 2024 - Present

- Frontend Development: Created responsive, user-friendly interfaces using React.js and Tailwind CSS, ensuring a seamless user experience across devices.
- **Backend Development:** Built and maintained server-side logic and API integrations using Node.js to deliver robust, scalable web applications.
- **Web Design:** Designed modern, visually appealing layouts and user interfaces focused on usability and aesthetics.
- Full Stack Maintenance: Managed and optimized APIs, databases, and full-stack systems, ensuring high performance and efficient data flow.
- **Website Deployment:** Deployed and managed websites using industry-standard tools and platforms, ensuring smooth and reliable site performance.

Freelance Frontend Developer

Project-Based Clients | February 2024 - April 2024

- Designed and developed user interfaces for various web applications and websites.
- Built responsive and user-friendly experiences across various platforms.
- Utilize strong skills in various web technologies to deliver highquality front-end solutions.

Programmer and IT Support

Library - CvSU - CCAT Campus | September 2023 - January 2024

- Provided comprehensive IT support services encompassing troubleshooting for computers, internet connectivity issues, and library system/software problems
- Designed and developed an executable for the library computer users monitoring system, allowing efficient student registration, PC user management, and report generation, prioritizing clear data entry and management for staffs.
- Utilized Python programming language to develop the UI and functions of the library computer monitoring system, ensuring a streamlined workflow for managing computer users access.

Sales Associates and Technician Assistant

Leoj Computer Center | October 2018 - January 2019

- Interact with customers, providing exceptional service and addressing their inquiries and process transactions accurately and efficiently.
- Troubleshoot technical issues and assist the lead technician in repairing and maintaining equipment and systems.
- Maintain accurate records of sales, inventory, and technical activities using appropriate software tools.

EDUCATION

BS in Information Technology

Cavite State University - CCAT Campus

Senior High School Diploma - TVL I.C.T.

Noveleta Senior High School

SKILLS

- Frontend and Backend Development
- Web and Mobile UI/UX Design
- Graphic Design
- Computer Software and Hardware

TECH STACK

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | PHP | Python | ReactJS | NodeJS | Shopify Liquid | Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS | Three JS | MySQL | Git

CERTIFICATES

DICT-ICT018 Basic Level of Software Engineering – Department of Information and Communications Technology (05/2024)

DICT-ICT013-Intermediate Level of Software Engineering - Department of Information and Communications Technology (05/2024)

DICT-ICT017 Advanced Level of Software Engineering - Department of Information and Communications Technology (05/2024)

PROJECTS

SOCA: AI-Powered Task Management System with Generative Text for Automated Subtask Generation (Web Technologies and MySQL and Cohere API)

Library Course-Based Computer Usage Monitoring System (Python)

Frontend Development Projects: Ecommerce Websites, Management Systems, Auditing System and Educational System (Web Technologies)